Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today Marco and I have an elementary level lesson for you.
我是Catherine，今天Marco和我为你们准备了一节初级课程。
That's right.
没错。
It's a new year and so we have a lesson for you where we are going to make new decisions
新年到了，所以我们有一节课，要和大家一起做新的决定，
and have a new opportunity in the new year, right?
并在新的一年里拥有新的机会，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So the new year is the time to change parts of your life maybe.
所以新年是改变你生活中某些部分的时候。
So that's what we're going to talk about today.
这就是我们今天要讨论的内容。
Let's listen to this dialogue three times and when we come back we'll be talking about
让我们听三遍这段对话，回来后我们会讨论
the words and phrases in the dialogue.
对话中的单词和短语。
Now that it's the new year, I've decided to turn over a new leaf.
既然现在是新年，我决定要改过自新。
Yeah?
是吗？
You finally decided to wipe the slate clean?
你终于决定要洗心革面了？
You got it.
你说对了。
I have a new job.
我有了新工作。
I'm living in a new city with new friends.
我住在一个新城市，交了一群新朋友。
This is my opportunity to make some small changes in the way I live my life.
这是我改变生活方式的好机会。
So what are you going to do?
那你打算做什么？
Take up an art class or something?
去上艺术课之类的？
Well first of all, I've decided to stop smoking.
首先，我决定戒烟。
It's not that I'm pinching pennies or anything.
倒不是因为我抠门什么的。
It's just that I've been smoking since I was 16 and I think it's time to stop.
只是我从16岁就开始抽烟，我觉得是时候戒掉了。
I'm with you on that one.
我支持你。
Anything else you're planning on doing?
你还有其他计划吗？
One last thing.
还有一件事。
I've decided to come out of the closet.
我决定出柜了。
It's about time.
是时候了。
Alright we're back and so if you notice the dialogue has actually a lot of really really
好了，我们回来了，如果你注意到，这段对话里其实有很多非常非常
rich phrases in there.
丰富的短语。
So today we're going to change the format a little bit and we're going to do Fluency
所以今天我们要稍微改变一下形式，分成两部分来做流利度训练。
Builder in two different sections.
先从第一部分开始，流利度训练第一部分。
So starting out with the first one on Fluency Builder part one.
流利度训练。
Fluency Builder.
So the new year we think about new things, changing things.
所以新年我们会想到新事物、改变事物。
We have a great phrase in English to describe starting fresh, starting anew.
英语里有一个很好的短语来形容重新开始、从头再来。
And we say turn over a new leaf.
我们说“turn over a new leaf”。
Okay so you turn over a new leaf.
好的，所以“turn over a new leaf”。
So that means that you are going to maybe make a radical change, right?
这意味着你可能会做出一个彻底的改变，对吧？
Completely new.
全新的开始。
That's right.
没错。
So if you think about it, it's a new chapter in your life or a new adventure or something
所以如果你想想，这就像你生命中的新篇章或新冒险之类的。
like that.
类似那样。
Maybe you're going to quit your job.
也许你会辞职。
Turn over a new leaf.
改过自新。
Start a new job.
开始新工作。
Okay.
好的。
So you can say I'm going to turn over a new leaf or Sarah turned over a new leaf and quit
所以你可以说“我要改过自新”或者“Sarah改过自新并戒了烟”。
smoking.
戒烟。
Let's turn over a new leaf and forget the past.
让我们改过自新，忘记过去。
There we go.
就是这样。
Alright so to turn over a new leaf.
好的，所以“turn over a new leaf”。
So just imagine that you have a leaf on the ground and you turn it over and it's nice
想象一下地上有一片叶子，你把它翻过来，它很干净。
and clean.
干净整洁。
Alright.
好的。
And talking about cleanliness, our second phrase is to wipe the slate clean.
说到干净，我们的第二个短语是“wipe the slate clean”。
Okay when I think about this phrase, I think about a chalkboard.
好的，当我想到这个短语时，我会想到一块黑板。
So a slate is like a chalkboard and all of the things that you've done, good and bad,
所以“slate”就像一块黑板，你做过的一切，好的和坏的，
are on that chalkboard.
都在那块黑板上。
And to wipe the slate clean means to erase those words, erase those things.
而“wipe the slate clean”就是擦掉那些字，擦掉那些事情。
So perhaps Marco and I fight all the time and we're angry at each other.
所以也许Marco和我总是吵架，彼此生气。
Finally I say listen, Marco, let's wipe the slate clean.
最后我说，听着，Marco，让我们洗心革面吧。
Let's forget the past.
让我们忘记过去。
Let's forget the things we said and start again.
忘记我们说过的话，重新开始。
Start a new leaf.
翻开新的一页。
To wipe the slate clean is to just start over.
“Wipe the slate clean”就是重新开始。
You know just to erase everything, let's forget about it and start over.
你知道，就是擦掉一切，让我们忘记它，重新开始。
Exactly.
没错。
Alright and so we're starting over and his friend is asking you decided to wipe the slate
好的，所以我们重新开始，他的朋友问你决定洗心革面了，
clean and the friend said you got it.
朋友说“你说对了”。
You got what?
你说对了什么？
What?
什么？
It.
它。
What is it?
它是什么？
In English we love the word it.
在英语里我们很喜欢“it”这个词。
Well in this case you got it means you're right exactly.
嗯，在这种情况下，“you got it”意思是你说得对。
You understand what I'm talking about.
你明白我在说什么。
Okay.
好的。
So if you agree with me or I understand what you're talking about you would say you got
所以如果你同意我，或者我明白你在说什么，你会说“you got
it.
it”。
You got it.
你说对了。
Alright so I'm trying to explain to you maybe Marco something very difficult like if you
好的，我试着跟你解释一些很难的东西，比如如果你
add four and ten you get fourteen but what if you add ten more?
四加十等于十四，但再加十呢？
It's twenty four.
是二十四。
You got it.
你说对了。
Alright.
好的。
Okay so he understands math.
好吧，所以他懂数学。
Yes.
是的。
Okay so that's the way you would use you got it.
好的，这就是“you got it”的用法。
It's a really popular phrase.
这是一个非常流行的短语。
I mean you can use it on pretty much anything not only if you're right but also if somebody
我的意思是，你几乎可以用在任何事情上，不仅是你答对了，还有如果某人
agrees with it or you promise something right.
同意或者你承诺某事的时候。
So are you going to pick me up today?
那你今天会来接我吗？
Yeah you got it.
好的，没问题。
Okay.
好的。
No problem.
没问题。
So it's a way to agree or to show that you're saying yes.
所以这是一种表示同意或说“是”的方式。
Yes.
是的。
Okay so why don't we listen to our dialogue again and we'll come back shortly to look
好的，那我们再听一遍对话，稍后回来继续看
at Fluency Builder part two.
流利口语第二部分。
Now that it's the new year I've decided to turn over a new leaf.
既然现在是新年，我决定改过自新。
Yeah?
是吗？
You finally decided to wipe the slate clean?
你终于决定重新开始了？
You got it.
你说对了。
I have a new job.
我有了新工作。
I'm living in a new city with new friends.
我住在一个新城市，有了新朋友。
This is my opportunity to make some small changes in the way I live my life.
这是我改变生活方式的机会。
So what are you going to do?
那你打算做什么？
Take up an art class or something?
报个艺术班之类的？
Well first of all I've decided to stop smoking.
首先，我决定戒烟。
It's not that I'm pinching pennies or anything it's just that I've been smoking since I was
不是因为我抠门什么的，只是我从十六岁就开始抽烟，
sixteen and I think it's time to stop.
我觉得是时候停了。
I'm with you on that one.
我支持你这个决定。
Anything else you're planning on doing?
你还有其他计划吗？
One last thing.
最后一件事。
I've decided to come out of the closet.
我决定出柜了。
It's about time.
是时候了。
Alright we're back so now let's continue with our Fluency Builder.
好的，我们回来了，现在继续我们的流利口语部分。
And well they kept talking and the guy mentioned that he's going to stop smoking.
他们继续聊，那个人提到他要戒烟。
But it's not because he is pinching pennies.
但不是因为他抠门。
Oh pinching.
哦，捏。
That sounds painful.
听起来很疼。
Right.
对。
Okay pinching is something you do especially when you're a child.
好的，“捏”是你小时候常做的事。
You squeeze the skin.
你掐皮肤。
Pinch and it hurts.
掐一下会疼。
So to pinch really is to hold something with two fingers.
所以“捏”真的就是用两个手指捏住东西。
To pinch pennies means to try to spend very very very little money.
“捏紧一分钱”意思是尽量花非常非常少的钱。
So if we say if I say hey Marco you want to go to dinner tonight?
所以如果我说，嘿，Marco，你今晚想去吃饭吗？
There's this really nice Italian place.
有一家很不错的意大利餐厅。
It's a little expensive but.
有点贵，但是……
Oh I can't I'm sorry.
哦，我去不了，抱歉。
I'm really pinching pennies these days because I'm kind of broke.
我最近真的很抠门，因为我有点没钱了。
So maybe we'll go somewhere cheaper.
所以我们可能去个便宜点的地方。
So actually pennies are one cent coins.
实际上，“pennies”是一分硬币。
They're called pennies in the United States.
在美国它们叫“pennies”。
That's right and it's the smallest kind of money that we have in America.
没错，这是美国最小的货币单位。
So if you're pinching pennies, if you're saving pennies, it means you really don't have much
所以如果你“捏紧一分钱”，如果你在省一分钱，意味着你真的没多少钱。
money.
钱。
You're really really saving.
你真的在拼命省钱。
That's right.
没错。
Okay so pinching pennies.
好的，所以“pinching pennies”。
So he decided to quit smoking and his friend agreed with him and said you know what I'm
所以他决定戒烟，他的朋友同意他，说你知道吗，我支持你这个决定。
with you on that one.
我支持你这个决定。
Okay so you quit smoking Marco and I quit smoking.
好的，所以你戒烟了，Marco，我也戒烟了。
I'm with you on that one.
我支持你这个决定。
I think it's a good idea.
我觉得这是个好主意。
If I'm with you on that one it means I agree with you.
如果我说“我支持你这个决定”，意思是我同意你。
You're doing the right thing.
你做得对。
So you can say I'm with you on that one or you can just say you know what I'm with you.
所以你可以说“我支持你这个决定”，或者直接说“你知道吗，我支持你”。
Do it.
去做吧。
I'm with you.
我支持你。
I agree.
我同意。
I'm with you.
我支持你。
I support your decision.
我支持你的决定。
So you are going to go skydiving in a couple weeks.
所以你几周后要去跳伞。
That means you're going to jump out of an airplane.
那意味着你要从飞机上跳下来。
I'm not with you on that one.
我不支持你这个决定。
You don't support my decision.
你不支持我的决定。
I think it's okay for you but I would not want to do it.
我觉得这对你来说没问题，但我不想这么做。
Alright.
好吧。
Right so you can do it in that way or just anything.
对，所以你可以那样做，或者随便什么方式。
You support somebody's decision.
你支持某人的决定。
I'm with you.
我支持你。
I'm with you on that one.
在那件事上我支持你。
Exactly.
没错。
Alright and our last phrase.
好了，我们最后一个短语。
To come out of the closet.
出柜。
So who's in the closet?
那谁在柜子里？
Why is somebody hiding in the closet?
为什么有人躲在柜子里？
Okay someone's not really hiding in the closet.
好吧，其实不是真的有人躲在柜子里。
This is a phrase we use to describe someone who is gay or lesbian who has a secret about
这是一个用来描述同性恋者的短语，他们对自己的
being a gay or lesbian.
同性恋身份保密。
So when they come out of the closet, they're telling their friends and family for the first
所以当他们出柜时，是第一次告诉朋友和家人
time that this is how they feel.
他们的真实感受。
So it's basically a phrase that's kind of a metaphor to say you know what I'm going
所以这基本上是一个比喻性的短语，意思是“你知道吗，我要
to tell everyone that I am gay or lesbian.
告诉所有人我是同性恋。”
That's right.
没错。
Well it's because in English often times a closet is a place where we keep secrets.
嗯，因为在英语中，柜子常常是藏秘密的地方。
So to come out of the closet means to share your secrets with people.
所以“出柜”意味着和别人分享你的秘密。
So sometimes in English you say you have skeletons in the closet.
所以有时在英语中，你会说“柜子里有骷髅”。
That's right.
没错。
This is a little different.
这有点不同。
Maybe I killed someone and it's a skeleton in my closet.
也许我杀了人，那是我柜子里的骷髅。
It's a secret that I keep.
那是我保守的秘密。
But a skeleton in your closet can also be a very big secret like you were once married
但“柜子里的骷髅”也可以指一个很大的秘密，比如你曾经结过婚
and you never told anyone.
但从未告诉任何人。
Yeah or I have two kids and I never told you guys.
是啊，或者我有两个孩子，但我从没告诉过你们。
Right.
对。
So those are the skeletons in the closet but in this case it's to come out of the closet
所以那些是“柜子里的骷髅”，但这里说的是“出柜”，
and that's always related to telling somebody for the first time that you are gay or lesbian.
而且总是和第一次告诉别人你是同性恋有关。
That's right and we don't say it about being straight which is the opposite which is men
没错，我们不会用它来形容异性恋，也就是男人
who love women and women who love men.
爱女人、女人爱男人的情况。
You don't say it about coming out of the closet there.
你不会说“出柜”来形容那种情况。
You say it about being gay or lesbian.
你只会用它来形容同性恋。
Okay.
好的。
So very interesting and so I think we should listen to this dialogue for the last time
所以非常有趣，我想我们应该最后听一遍这段对话，
and we'll be back to talk a little bit more.
然后回来再聊一点。
Now that it's the new year I've decided to turn over a new leaf.
既然现在是新年，我决定改过自新。
Yeah.
是啊。
You finally decided to wipe the slate clean.
你终于决定把过去一笔勾销了。
You got it.
你说对了。
I have a new job.
我有了新工作。
I'm living in a new city with new friends.
我住在一个新城市，有了新朋友。
This is my opportunity to make some small changes in the way I live my life.
这是我改变生活方式的好机会。
So what are you going to do?
那你打算做什么？
Take up an art class or something?
报个艺术班之类的？
Well first of all I've decided to stop smoking.
嗯，首先我决定戒烟。
It's not that I'm pinching pennies or anything.
倒不是因为我抠门什么的。
It's just that I've been smoking since I was 16 and I think it's time to stop.
只是我从16岁就开始抽烟，我觉得是时候戒了。
I'm with you on that one.
在那件事上我支持你。
Anything else you're planning on doing?
你还打算做别的吗？
One last thing.
最后一件事。
I've decided to come out of the closet.
我决定出柜。
It's about time.
是时候了。
All right we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So this is very interesting and these phrases are so common because if you have a fight
所以这非常有趣，这些短语很常见，因为如果你和别人吵架了，
with somebody you say, you know what, let's just wipe the slate clean and start all over
你会说，“你知道吗，让我们把过去一笔勾销，重新开始”，
again or let's turn over a new leaf.
或者“让我们改过自新”。
Let's stop fighting.
别吵了。
And especially in New Year's, right, everyone makes a promise to start fresh.
尤其是在新年，对吧，每个人都承诺要重新开始。
That's right.
没错。
Well the new year you can use a new calendar.
嗯，新年你可以用一本新日历。
You can take a fresh perspective on your life.
你可以用全新的视角看待生活。
It's refreshing and I think it's good that we do this.
这让人耳目一新，我觉得我们这样做很好。
We evaluate the things that make us happy and we evaluate the things that make us unhappy
我们评估那些让我们快乐的事，也评估那些让我们不快乐的事，
and part of that means turning over a new leaf.
其中一部分就是改过自新。
Part of it also means apologizing to people or trying to make the relationships in your
另一部分也包括向别人道歉，或者努力让你生活中的
life healthier.
关系更健康。
And I think it's very healthy that the person in this dialogue says, listen, I'm finally
而且我觉得这段对话中的人说“听着，我终于要
going to come out of the closet.
出柜了”是非常健康的。
I'm going to be honest with my friends and family.
我要对朋友和家人诚实。
And that's really interesting because as we said, to come out of the closet is a phrase
这真的很有趣，因为正如我们所说，“出柜”是一个
used in English and mostly related only in this context so you might see it in TV shows
英语中使用的短语，大多只在这个语境下使用，所以你可能会在电视节目
or in a movie.
或电影中看到它。
But it's an interesting topic, still debatable all over the world about gay marriages and
但这是一个有趣的话题，全世界关于同性婚姻
things like that.
之类的事情仍有争议。
That's right.
没错。
So we're curious about your New Year's resolutions.
所以我们很好奇你的新年决心。
Are you going to be wiping any slates clean?
你打算把过去一笔勾销吗？
Are you going to be doing anything differently this year?
你今年打算做些什么不一样的事吗？
Let us know on our website, EnglishPod.com.
在我们的网站 EnglishPod.com 上告诉我们吧。
We look forward to hearing from you and until next time.
我们期待你的消息，下次再见。
Bye everyone.
大家再见。
Happy New Year.
新年快乐。